♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ way down in deep 13 ♪
♪ Dr. Forrester and TV's frank ♪
♪ were hatching
an evil scheme ♪
♪ they hired a temp
by the name of Mike ♪
♪ just a regular Joe
they didn't like ♪
♪ their experiment needed
a good test case ♪
♪ so they conked him
on the noggin ♪
♪ and they
shot him into space ♪
Let... me... gooo!
♪ We'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ the worst we can find ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ he'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ and we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ now, keep in mind
Mike can't control ♪
♪ where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ he'll try to keep
his sanity ♪
♪ with the help
of his robot friends ♪
♪ robot roll call ♪
- Cambot.
- Kill yourself.
- Gypsy.
- [Squeaking]
- Tom Servo.
- Hello there!
- Croooow!
- That's guano.
♪ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
♪ and other science facts ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ just repeat to yourself ♪
♪ it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ for "mystery science
theater 3000" ♪♪
[Thud, creaking]
[Beeping]
[Zoom]
[Water bubbling]
[Crash]
[Grinding]
[Laughter]
- Good one!
- Thank you.
Oh, hi, everybody!
Welcome to the satellite
of love here.
- That's crow.
- Hi!
I'm Tom,
and I'll get Mike.
Hey, Mike!
[Laughing]
You're just in time to read
tonight's lotto numbers!
Oh, I didn't know
that we were gonna--
here you go.
And the first number is...
65.
Whoa, uh, seven.
- Oh, uh, 69.
- 69, heh heh heh.
We got a 12.
We got--
how many of these lotto numbers
do we need?
Oh, you need a lot o'
lotto numbers, Mike.
Okay, uh, four, four.
- [Laughing]
- Here we go!
[Laughing]
Two, 27.
- Look alive.
- 47!
- We'll be right back.
- Uhh!
Oh, yeah!
Come on, Mike,
you missed that one!
- On your toes, baby!
- Okay, 84, 48!
- Ha ha!
- Whoa!
That is three.
- Three.
- Okay, 800.
- 800!
And tonight's powerball number
is...
- [Grunts]
- Uhh!
5-0-9.
- 5-0-9.
- 5-0-9!
5-0-9.
Oh, ace and no-face
are calling.
- 5-0-9.
- Powerball.
Oh, hi, Mike.
Say, have you ever been
in deep with the mob for,
oh, say... 50 large?
Heh heh.
Uh, no, I don't think so.
Is there a problem
or something?
Oh, nothing, nothing.
It's just that, well...
[Chuckles]
I'm in deep
to the mob for 50 large.
[Chuckling]
Oh, well.
[Doorbell rings]
I'll see who--
ah!
Oh ho ho...
You must be here
to see TV's frank.
I'll go see if TV's frank
is here.
[Chuckling]
Uh, Clay?
Clay, uh, there's
a Joey "skinny legs" tagliano
here to see you.
- Hmm?
- Joe "skinny legs"...
- Tagliano?
- Yeah, to see you.
Did I go to high school
with him?
I bet that's what it is,
I went to high school.
Joe?
Hello?
Whoa, whoa!
[Thudding]
Oh! Oh! Ahh!
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
- I...
- Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Gee, I feel kinda bad
about this.
Oh, wow! Wow!
I must admit, I feel partly
responsible, heh.
Kind of, heh.
Sort of.
[Chuckling]
I wouldn't worry about it,
frank.
Ah, Nelson!
Awfully good evening,
isn't it?
Naturally, one would find
a gentlemen such as yourself
at the gaming tables.
Yes, yes, yes,
Mr. Crow.
Where was it last we met?
Was it Atlantic city,
monte Carlo...
Grand casino hinckley?
[Laughing]
You're very droll.
Yes, yes, indeed, Nelson.
Why, here comes Tom Servo.
Gentlemen.
Yes, yes,
sorry I'm late, chums.
The house extended me a $100,000
line of credit, you know,
and I always like
to show the proper gratitude.
You know what I mean?
Yes, yes.
[All laughing]
Yes, well, let the games begin,
eh, gentlemen?
Yes, oh, wonderful.
[On pa]
B-37.
Ah, yes, oh!
Congratulations,
Mr. Nelson.
But, as they say,
the night is still young, what?
[All laughing]
Yes, yes, yes.
- Very true.
- Yes, yes.
There, there, Dr. F.
There, there.
Oh, hi, guys.
Uh, your movie today--
your movie is, uh,
"red zone Cuba."
But first,
there's a short.
[Groaning]
And then if Dr. Forrester lives
through this, he's going to...
[Grunting]
... beat the living crap--
[chuckles]
Well...
Enjoy the experiment, guys.
Hey, look, Dr. F.,
I got you something.
Some nuts
and some hard-boiled eggs.
[Whimpers]
[Pa]
Attention, attention.
The buffet
is now being served.
[All]
The buffet!
Okay, okay, clear out!
Gah!
[Overlapping chatter]
♪♪
[Humming]
- Speech!
Speech!
Hey, "posture pals"
was the definitive last word
on posture.
Did ancient toastmasters
make this film?
♪♪
"Professor buehler's day off"!
There were a lot of forensics
going on in Kansas in the '50s.
The ear is the human organ
the public speaker
is most likely to try to impress
as he makes
a speech.
After the human nipple.
But did you ever think
of the importance of the eye?
The importance
of what the listener sees
as well as hears?
"The eyes of Kenneth Mars."
Now just suppose you were
a beautiful doll
with rosy cheeks
and big, blue eyes.
- Okay.
- A doll that never talks.
Just do what he says.
Or a tree that basked
in the warm sunshine
and rustled
in the breeze.
A tree that never spoke.
Now you're
a can opener!
Metal and shiny
and taciturn.
Or suppose you were
a spring flower,
contrasting your gay colors
with the blue sky.
I'm not a flower.
Do you know how
you would be judged?
You'd be judged mostly by your
appearance, by the way you look.
By the kind of car
you drive.
Appearance is the basis
upon which a little girl
chooses a new doll.
I like this one,
'cause it's whiter.
[Giggles]
A man's prosperity
is often judged
by the appearance of his home,
and thus, is man himself judged.
Yes, that's
eisenhower's america.
Yes, appearance is important.
There, I said it.
I'd say it again
if I had to.
Appearance
is a powerful factor.
I learned that the hard way.
And appearance is something
you can control.
Remember, "appearance"
has a "pear" in it.
In public speaking,
your appearance
may make the difference between
a good speech and a poor one.
Your appearance may help
convince your audience
you know
what you're talking about,
or it may convince them
you don't know
what you're talking about.
Of course, I don't know
what I'm talking about.
A good appearance is something
that everyone should strive for,
something everyone
can accomplish.
Let me just get my notes here.
I know I had
something else.
It begins with the feet.
Seems strange,
but having your shoes shined
will help you make
a better speech.
It will help
your general appearance
and make you feel better.
Plus, the Polish
gets you high!
And you should have your suit
cleaned and pressed
just for your talk.
This will help you
look successful.
Hey, honey, you're supposed
to take the paper off.
Be sure to wear
a clean shirt.
Be sure
to get a brand-new chin.
And your favorite tie.
Now you're ready to rub out
Sonny corleone.
Be sure your hair
is neat and clean,
and you're all ready to go.
Make sure your part
is gouged into your skull.
Yes, sir, you're all dressed up
and you're ready to go.
You feel great--
but wait a minute.
There's a lot more
to appearance
than just having your
necktie straight,
your hair combed,
and your teeth brushed.
The most important one element
of your appearance
is your posture.
Not that it helps
this guy any, hee hee.
Your posture may be more
convincing to your audience
than the words
you say to them.
Depending upon your posture,
this can be good or bad...
Poo-poo, caca, sissypants.
[Muttering]
... because your audience
subconsciously judges you
as much by what they see
as what they hear you say,
and they'll see you
before they hear you.
The effectiveness
of a brilliant speech
can be greatly diminished
by poor posture.
- Ugh!
- Ooh!
[Coughing]
'Cause we like you.
Because your audience
thinks about what they see
as well as what they hear.
It's the village
of the damned!
If your posture is poor,
your audience thinks,
"this poor fellow isn't sharp."
He's weary and confused.
He doesn't care about us,
and he probably doesn't know
what he's talking about.
And you,
you are puzzled.
Why has your speech failed?
Uh, ever seen
a one-eared elephant?
Mister, you don't look good,
that's why.
What your audience sees
is so bad,
they can't hear
what you're saying.
He's got Patty Duke's dad
in his contact lens.
Now, good platform posture
can be accomplished
by anyone
with a little effort
and concentration.
Good posture is,
first, a physical matter.
The body should be held erect
and tall, with the head up.
Secondly, good posture
is a matter of the mind.
Your mind.
In your thinking,
you must convince yourself
you will think tall, talk tall,
stand tall, and walk tall.
Shave tall,
jump tall, and crouch tall.
Remember that you
must think tall.
Mm-hmm.
Talk tall.
Stand tall.
And walk tall.
This will help you with your
posture and your speech.
What if you're
Robert reich?
Now, good posture serves
more of a purpose
than just
making you look better.
It helps you to be
comfortable
because it keeps you
well-balanced on the platform.
America first!
Poor balance, along
with poor posture, causes
some of the characteristic types
of speakers you have seen.
This type knows his subject
and has good control
of his voice, but look at him.
He looks almost too tired
to stand up.
Women be different than men!
Word.
He balances
first on one leg,
then on the other.
Ahh.
- Ooh!
- [Wolf whistle]
That's really very good.
He's the tired
farm horse type.
She's an energetic city girl.
Can they get along
in the suburbs?
Then there's miss prim,
the speaker who stands straight,
tall, and rigid.
She seems to be afraid
she'll break,
and she looks frightened
and excessively formal.
And yet startlingly erotic.
[Giggles]
♪ Wouldn't it be loverly ♪
She keeps her feet
clamped tightly together.
'Nuff said.
We know her
as the telephone pole type.
♪ Hi-yo-ta-ho ha! ♪
Next, we have the he-man
athletic type.
- Grandpa?
- You've often seen him.
He stands with his shoulders
back and his stomach out
and his feet wide apart.
-He looks undignified,
and soon his awkward posture
- tires him...
- Il duce.
...and he rocks back and forth
for relief.
The lions sense his weakness
and close in,
chewing at his hamstrings.
[Imitating creaking noise]
He is
the rocking horse type.
She's a straight-back chair
type.
Can they get along?
Lastly, we come to the type
who leans.
He leans on the table,
back of a chair,
or anything handy.
In trying to be
nonchalant and at ease,
he makes himself thoroughly
uncomfortable.
The belching
doesn't help, either.
Plus, he's leaning on the people
in the front row.
He is the turtle type.
All four common types
look awkward,
partially because
they're off-balance.
Good balance results
from having the bodily weight
well-distributed
on both feet,
and in having the feet
just the right distance apart
- for comfort.
- [Wolf whistle]
You can determine this distance
by making the knee test.
I will not
make the knee test.
Place the palms of your hands
on both knees.
Wait, I'm kidding!
Make an easy circular motion
with the hands and knees.
Until you're
incredibly turned on.
If your feet are the correct
distance apart,
the weight will be
evenly distributed
as you change position.
You'll be well balanced
and comfortable.
You'll look
poised and dignified.
Uh, no, you won't.
With your feet
too far apart,
you'll have difficulty
in standing up.
Because you're off-balance,
you may fall either forward
or backward.
Don't do this
during the speech.
With your feet
too close together,
you're still off balance
and you're uncomfortable.
That's fine...
Security!
That's really nice.
Uh, is your speech over,
Mr. Johnson?
Uh, good.
Try it until you find
the easiest
and most
comfortable position,
then note the location
of your feet.
Yeah, that's it, baby,
shake that moneymaker!
Always try to keep your feet
in this position
when you are speaking,
and you won't have
to worry about balance.
And with good balance,
you've conquered another phase
of good appearance.
[Humming theme
from "my three sons"]
Now remember that appearance
is important.
You must appear,
and you must have matter.
And that good appearance
is easily accomplished.
Except by Denny Dillon.
Just remember
to think tall...
Talk tall...
Stand tall...
And walk tall,
and to achieve good balance.
For good posture
and appearance
will greatly increase
your ability as a speaker
and a leader.
And remember to always leave
your area at home.
My posture is good!
[Screeches like an eagle]
Eagle.
No, cut, no.
Do it again.
Well, this is a sunny opening.
Mm-hmm.
Says, "lutheran
pacific railroad."
- Hmm.
To get a good job,
get a good education.
Um, hello?
Do you have a brunch?
John carradine.
Was he always 100 years old?
Mm-hmm.
John carradine for viceroy.
Sal mineo for viceroy.
I'll keep walking, and
eventually they'll stop filming.
John really fills out a pair
of overalls, doesn't he?
Hmm, station is really bustling
this time of day.
Huh?
Mr. Wilson?
That's right.
What can I
do for you, young man?
My name's Jim Benton,
from the gazette.
I'm doing a follow-up story
on the desperados
that were through here in '61.
Ah, yes, yes.
Which century?
I remember those men.
Griffin, cook, and landis.
I believe you were
engineer
on the train
they grabbed that night.
Yeah, that's right.
Choo-choo Charlie
was my name.
I was making
a run Albuquerque.
That was in '61.
Then I joined
the crash test dummies.
Did you happen to see the men
in the yard that night, sir?
No, at least not
close enough to recognize them.
As I pulled out
of the yard that night,
I remember looking back
for the conductor's signal.
I saw some men running.
It was dark.
Yes, sir?
That's not enough?
[Chuckles]
That seems like
a long time ago.
Kid looks like a reporter
from the "catholic digest."
Griffin.
John makes Keith Richards
look dewy.
He ran all the way to hell.
But there's always
a stop in wausau.
How's that fit you,
fancy pants?
♪♪
The red zone is for Cuba
and UN-Cuba only.
You know, I've got
an oily Cuba zone.
Coleman Francis is curly Howard
in "the fugitive."
Hey, moe!
Oh, he's good in anything.
Mm-hmm.
What's that music?
What the--
oh, I'm being filmed, oh.
This was just after he was
drained of life by the succubus.
♪ Night train to mundo fine ♪
Well, they don't call
John carradine "the voice"
for nothing.
♪ Night train to the end ♪
Oh, to be blessed with
an instrument like that.
♪ Running hard
and running fast ♪
♪ to meet my future
and away from my past ♪
♪ taking the gamble
that cannot last ♪
♪ night train to the end ♪
Ha, he's trying
to sneak into China.
♪ Hell's ride to mundo fine ♪
[Whistling]
- Low keys.
- Hey.
♪ Hell's ride to the end ♪
Ho, now, I'm rocking.
♪ Sold my soul
to the devil's bend ♪
♪ drawing me hard with
a merciless hand ♪
♪ and all I bought
is a handful of sand ♪
♪ night train to the end ♪
Whoops, there
we go again.
♪ Night train to the end ♪
Jeez, this escape route
is used a lot.
There's all the malt cups
from his previous takes.
Shake it!
Get down, now, boogie man!
Whoa!
Play that funky music.
♪ Drink night train ♪
♪ go to the basketball game ♪
♪ throw up
under the bleachers ♪
Moe is gonna kill me!
Ow, ow, ow...
We join our story,
already in progress.
[Grunting like curly]
Lord be with you.
[Crickets chirping]
Changing a tire
without a license, huh?
[Metal clanks]
Move back.
Come here, you.
You look good,
been working out?
What's your name?
Cook.
All right,
stand back there, cook.
There'll be no tire changing
in my county, mister.
[Giggling]
That tickles!
What's your name?
Landis.
Where you going?
Looking for work.
We follow the harvest.
Crops froze up north,
we're heading south.
No work to be found nowhere,
officer.
You seen anyone
around here?
Uh, the field, maybe?
No, we ain't,
officer.
I'll have to run you
through the computer.
Well, I would if I had one.
Crap, I'm locked
out of my car.
Crotch cops.
♪ This is my country ♪
Attention, all cars report
to three forks, immediately.
What did we do?
Boy, he's nothing
if not thorough.
All right, get that truck out
of here or I'll run you both in!
Oh, so it's martial law
in rat's ass Missouri.
See what happened?
Get out of my way.
Well, you're the one
who wanted to stop here.
I don't know why you had to stop
here in the first place.
Ow!
I fell on my hubcap.
Stupid, get in the stupid
truck...
We just gotta get this thing
on and then we'll--
shut up, shh, no!
Damn tire changers!
[Dogs barking]
Sometimes walking the dog
just isn't that relaxing.
Oh, Tony Curtis and Sidney
poitier are in there already.
You know,
this movie can't decide
if it's lighthearted comedy
or gripping drama.
♪♪
Snausages...
Ow, my area!
[All howling]
Thanks, now I'm barren!
Hoo hoo!
Phew! It smells like
Coleman Francis in here.
[Yawns] I'm tired,
been a long day.
[Feigns snoring]
♪ Running down the road
trying to loosen my load ♪
♪ I got Coleman Francis
on my mind ♪
Well, this film
wastes no precious screen time
with a plot.
♪♪
- Oh!
- Yeah.
Well, this film is moving along
quite briskly.
♪♪
♪♪ [humming]
How's your pasta?
Well, look who's finally up.
Wub-wub-wub-
wub-wub-wub-wub!
I really enjoy
our progressive dinners.
Do I just seat myself, then?
Ugh, were you
saving a specimen?
[Chuckles]
No need for that gun.
Sit down.
Have some coffee.
[Coyote howls]
Few beans left.
No need to make a fuss.
Oh, pshaw.
There's always too many beans.
I thought
I heard something
in the back of that truck
last night.
But I was too lazy
to turn my head and look.
Yeah, thanks, boys,
I really shouldn't,
but, oh, what the heck,
it's Thanksgiving, heh heh.
Fresh ground pepper, sir?
My name's cook.
Landis.
We've been up the river.
[Chuckling]
That's my little joke.
You sure fooled us, though,
last night.
You must have
been right by his car.
What'd you do?
Grab our tailgate
when we drove off?
Me and landis
got busted back in '58.
Liquor store.
Two years of hard labor.
Now we're grabbing a job
anywhere we find it.
No more iron cages.
Sorry I blew up like that.
Coffee?
And thus
a solid friendship is born.
Ah, that's mighty good
beet juice.
Ohh.
[Coyote howling]
This is a hazelnut sumatra
blend.
I think
you'll like it.
Anyone for tiramisu?
♪♪
Oh, no, the lunch rush!
Oh, my ride's here,
gotta get my purse.
Hi, I brought
your new script pages.
Buford pusser,
"walking dense."
You boys just drive down
from the north?
Think, damn it.
Yes, sir.
Mm-hmm.
[Imitating Elvis]
Thank you very much.
Didn't happen to see
a big fella,
about 200 pounds,
maybe, hitchhiking?
No, sir, we didn't.
Uh-huh.
Do you provide a service
of some sort?
Uh-huh.
All right, boys,
all right.
Damn, he's good.
Uh, just in case you do,
his name is Griffin,
and the reward is $5,000.
[All]
He's over there!
Right there!
Right in the bushes!
Griffin'll kill you.
Ooh,
kill you, yes.
Gilligan!
Oh, oh!
Oh, he's a regular
Mycroft Holmes.
Agh, let me just hoist
my large ass in here, ohh.
Once we get past
the character development,
this film's bound
to pick up.
Oh, yeah, heh heh.
Ah, yes, yes.
Well, I don't know
about you chaps,
but I'm still in the mood
for some action.
Ah, well, then some high-stakes
pull-tabs, perhaps?
Ooh, I'm getting
a rush already!
Why don't we check
on Dr. Forrester, okay?
Oh, all right.
If you say so.
[Sighs]
So it's come to this, huh?
Are you just
gonna lie there
like a big lump,
feeling sorry for yourself?
Is that it?
Are you gonna let a couple
of scratch and bruises
turn you into a self-pitying
sissypants?
Well, are you?!
Are you?!
Look at me
when I'm speaking to you!
[Groaning]
I don't believe this.
I'm very, very disappointed.
The old Clayton forrester
wasn't like this at all.
He didn't know
the meaning of the word quit.
He didn't have it in him!
The old
Dr. Clayton forrester
would have thrown off
these covers.
He would have
pulled himself up!
[Groans loudly]
He would have pulled
his twisted knees over
and stood himself up
on his own two casts.
[Crack]
Agh!
That's the Dr. Clayton forrester
that I know.
But, oh, that posture!
- [Whimpering]
- Here.
[Crack]
Ogh!
- There.
- [Groaning]
Okay, let's have at it.
Let's go, come on.
[Whimpering]
Ugh, man.
I can hardly stand to watch.
Yeah, I know, his posture
is really terrible.
The worst!
Yeah, poor frank's
got his work cut out for him.
- That's for sure.
- We'll be right back.
His posture's--
I didn't mean his posture.
[Humming]
He didn't say anything.
Nothin' happened.
You've got it all wrong.
We just made out
for a while.
You were wonderful.
Boy, never before has the screen
been so electrified.
Ah, you were wonderful.
We lead a rich life.
That kind of money's
worth joining up for.
They give you
a thousand bucks to join
and a thousand bucks
when it's over.
That's at least
a thousand bucks.
Maybe it won't be over.
Oh, you're deep,
Tony, real deep.
Once we get that money
in our hands,
we'll grab
a long freight train.
"Cherokee-Jack"...
Hey, wait, we didn't finish
reading the sign!
U.S. air
needs to update a bit.
Suddenly it's "the best years
of our lives."
[Humming]
Buddy hackett.
Hey.
There'll be a five-hour delay in
our movie, so please stand by.
We'll have the mechanic take
a look at it, and meanwhile,
we'll have to ask you
to board another movie.
He did it again!
You think they'd be
on to him by now.
[Scoffs]
[Humming]
Ah, another
Hollywood pretty boy.
Take a long second and get used
to this face.
Cherokee Jack?
Yeah, I'm cherokee Jack.
Do you know where they train men
to fight down in Cuba?
Yeah, I know
where they train.
How much to fly us
to the training camp?
$15 each.
We're about busted.
What'll you give us
for the truck?
Run good?
Throw in the guy?
Let's look at it.
I'm cherokee Jack.
Oh, no, you ran over my dog!
$35.
Mmm, 12,000.
$35?
That's the best
I can do, boys.
Well, that's
not too bad.
How about our friend?
Tell you what
I'll do, boys.
You give me the truck,
I'll fly the three of you.
Well, all right,
cherokee.
When can we leave?
Tonight.
I'm cherokee Jack!
It's petey the plane!
Hey, petey!
[Propeller rumbling]
Coleman Francis makes
terrific stories.
Well, the close-ups
really save on sets.
That nose wheel
feels mushy.
Uh, weren't they just flying?
Mind if we pick up
my flight instructor?
I've got a few lessons left.
Last known photo.
Just think, the tape deck alone
is worth $35.
Just makes me mad.
We're just gonna roll there,
right?
♪ Da, da da da ♪
♪ da, da da da ah ♪
Look, a soccer team.
If you need any help...
Just press
the stewardess button.
... my friend here can fly.
[Thunder crashes]
Mind if I smoke?
Thanks, good.
I'll smoke then.
You're sitting on my hand.
[Thunder crashes]
It's really
coming down, huh?
Wait a minute,
it's beautiful!
[Laughter]
Mom, they're landing
in our yard!
They've flown all the way
from new Mexico to new Mexico.
I can't handle the truth!
Oh, they're here!
Gah.
Oh, god, that's over.
Ptth! Ohh.
I hope he's here to brief us
on the movie.
I brought you
some fightin' men, Joe.
Good, we can use them.
Okay, men,
follow me.
I'm cherokee Jack.
Well, men, I'll fill you in
on who you are
and where you came from
and why you're here and...
Some of the hottest minders
in Hollywood.
Well, the bears
are acting up,
so be careful and keep
your campfires small.
Gentlemen, we shove off
in 24 hours.
- You shove off!
- Haven't time for formalities.
That was an official thing
I just did.
Here's the lunch menu,
just check off what you want.
[Crickets chirping]
Boy, they got
a real cricket problem.
- What's this?
- Sign your name.
What for?
For headquarters
to make out your checks.
Is, uh, "x" okay?
We get cash.
- Cherokee said--
- sign your names, please.
[Birds tweeting]
Hey, quit bilocating.
Boy, look at him.
He's guarding the hell
out of that place.
Yes, earth shelter housing is
the choice for guerilla groups.
Remember, guys, no girls
allowed in our fort.
My name's chastain.
Justine?
Where you fellas from?
Up north.
Do you know Bob?
Let's get something to eat.
See you around.
I think I really
drew them out.
♪ You can take Salem
out of the country ♪
♪ but, ding, you can't take
the country out of Salem ♪
Ah, my first good shower
in months.
Could you
sponge my back, Steve?
Hurry up.
I would never want to go
in after Coleman.
Come on, how long
you gonna take in there?
That should be all right.
Yeah?
Yeah, that's perhaps
the logical spot, chastain.
Sergeant justine, I want you
to call me lieutenant Vivian.
We'll hit the beach...
Here.
You smell great, sir.
I'll have Jimmy and the three
that came in tonight.
Those three?
You're right, I'm sorry.
How much help can we expect
from them?
I don't know.
I think we're being watched
by a winslow homer painting.
They're broke.
Probably hiding from the law.
Who knows?
But they are
coming with us.
How much help,
I don't know.
Jose will drop
the ropes... here.
'Cause it's Cuba.
Alive with pleasure.
Ah, they're filming in someone's
basement apartment.
Hmm.
Do you guys think
that justine guy is cute?
Must be a railroad highway
somewhere around here.
I'd do five years to get that
cherokee throat in my hands.
Nothing I hate
more than a liar.
Don't worry...
We'll get out of here.
Well, I feel better
just talking about it.
Thanks, guys.
Our auteur,
ladies and gentlemen.
Honey, you up?
[Knock on door]
Turn-down service.
Come in, chastain.
Hour after hour
of heart-pounding small talk.
♪♪
So you guys want to mess around
and overthrow Cuba or something?
Nice evening.
What can we
do for you?
Oh, it's getting
sort of lonely.
So I thought I'd get
some news from civilization.
Arizona, maybe.
Arizona, huh?
Out around Pearl.
They have a ranch there.
How'd you get caught
in that?
My grandparents
live in Cuba.
Their sugar mill
was taken away.
Now it's a nutrasweet mill.
Oh, I don't know, i--
I figured they
have a right to it.
You got your first money?
Cash?
Afraid not--
this one is on me.
What does that mean?
"What does that mean?"
It means I'm gonna try
and help my grandparents
get their mill back.
It sounds sort of foolish,
doesn't it?
- Nice plywood guitar.
- [Giggles]
Guess I'm a dreamer.
Aren't we all?
My wife, Ruby,
says I'm a dreamer.
They financed me four years
of college.
Figured, oh,
it was something--
but enough of that.
[Chuckles]
Ah, I know.
This is the gomer pyle exhibit
at filmways land.
"Full metal curly."
I always wanted money...
But I settled
for looks.
... a lot of money.
If we stick together,
maybe we can get money.
Somewhere.
Where does the pillow end
and his face begin?
If the boys back at the joint
could see me now.
Aw, Coleman hogged
all the best lines for himself.
Going to fight for some peasants
in Cuba.
[Laughing]
I had to finish smoking before
I could find that amusing.
Griffin, how did you
bust out?
You never told us
much about that.
[Clearing throat]
Drain pipe.
Dug up some dirt.
Shut up, everyone,
he's gonna tell the dirt
and the drain pipe story,
shh!
I worked
three long months.
Griffin.
Seems like
I read about a Griffin once.
They called him the cotton king
of the south.
This film
dares you to watch it.
Sold a lot of cotton one day.
That night, sent his trucks in
and stole it right back.
They sent him up
for a long stretch.
It seems like
a thousand years ago.
His wife spent all the money
and become a streetwalker.
Every newspaper in the south
had a picture of her.
Well, that's a weird stain.
A beautiful broad.
♪♪
Ah! It's my incessant droning,
isn't it?
That's it, yeah.
There, now can we
get some sleep?
I'm just in a bad mood,
I'm sorry.
[Sniffling]
I'm so sorry.
May I finish my story?
I think you're supposed
to strangle me till I'm dead.
This is gonna be hard to ignore,
fella.
[Groaning]
- Ooh.
- Oh?
We've got the gravel pit
till noon,
and then the sandinistas
are scheduled.
[Humming]
Hey, Van cliburn.
[Laughing]
Ha, they're at bus driver
training!
Hi-Cuba!
[Guffaws]
Ah, Castro doesn't
stand a chance.
Okay, now,
what we want to do here is--
hey, where are you going?
Do you really need
to practice jumping?
Uhh! All right, I'm sitting
on a spike-- you can't move me.
[Grunting]
Ooh.
It's the shining path
fantasy camp.
[Humming]
Les steckel
begins training camp.
♪♪
[Humming]
Uhh! Oof!
[Giggles]
I don't want
to be covert anymore.
We do more before noon than most
people do before 10:00!
That was very good, Jimmy.
"That was very good,
Jimmy."
It was nice of Mrs. Mimbock
to let them use her back yard.
We're gonna make it.
Now's the time.
We'll hide out
till they shove off.
You shove off!
Coleman's think tank.
[Chuckles]
Let's make a run for it.
Well, make a jog for it,
anyway.
Halt!
And their highly-detailed plan
falls apart.
Ah, the revolution
is highly underfunded.
Not me.
Let Jimmy try his look.
Come on, ed,
roll 'em.
Hey, where Tom Arnold
lives now.
[Laughter]
Oh, they got caught
and now they're forced to just
hang out somewhere, huh?
Come on, boy.
Come on,
treat your daddy right.
I need a pair of shoes.
And a hat
and a purse.
- Yahtzee!
- Snake eyes.
[Humming]
Hey, it's fee waybill.
You boys want to play
some gallopin' dominos?
What?
You wanna shoot some dice?
Maybe play
some freeze tag?
Agh, I see!
Well, perhaps I'll ask you
again later, ow.
Men, I want you to study
this picture my son drew.
Men, we're shoving off
right after sundown.
[All]
You shove off!
I wanted to give you some idea
of what to expect.
There's 80,000 of them
and seven of us.
At 12:00 midnight,
we hit the beach.
At 12:30, a patrol boat
makes its nightly run.
We have 30 minutes
to scale 80-foot cliffs
and clear the beach.
Ted, you take Havana.
We fight if we have to.
Our job is to tear down
telephone lines,
destroy all forms of
communication, ammo dumps.
We have a man in Cuba
that'll pull ropes over
the cliff at 12:00 midnight.
At 12:15, we're captured.
We must not
get caught on the beach.
Especially with my thighs.
[Shudders]
The invasion force
will follow us.
They should
be there at daybreak.
Any questions?
Yeah, are your bunkmates
supposed to strangle you?
Okay, men, that's it.
Start getting
your gear ready.
Gear?
Be ready to shove off
right after sundown.
[All]
You shove off!
Careful with those cigars.
It's the ghost brigade.
[Humming marching music]
Wow, what
an awesome sight.
Uh-huh.
♪ A kiss on the hand ♪
♪ may be quite continental ♪
Uh, Mike?
What are you doing?
Oh, I'm sorry,
Mike's not here.
I'm Carol Channing.
I'd be glad to bring a message
to this-- Mike, was it?
Oh, I see.
Oh, this movie must have really
gotten to you, poor sap.
[Imitating Carol Channing]
Well, it's just sensational
that you're
Carol Channing!
- [Laughing]
- What are you doing?
Hey, stop that.
As Carol Channing, I must say,
that is very annoying.
Ohh.
We better check
on frank and Dr. F., eh?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Well, you do whatever
you want.
I'm lunching
with Angela lansbury.
- Uh...
Heh heh heh.
I, uh...
Happy talk,
talk about the things--
oh, hi!
Well, I guess
it's pretty inevitable now.
Basically, it's a waiting game
at this point.
I've decided not to employ
any radical procedures.
Water.
Sorry, Clay.
It's pretty hopeless.
Been going through your mail,
though.
Oh, look at this.
It's a card
from Leo buscaglia.
"Hope you die,
you rotten bast..."
[Chuckling]
Oh, well.
[Phone ringing]
- Hello?
- Hello, frank?
It's Jimmy Carter.
Yes, Mr. President?
Is he dead yet?
I'll let you know
just as soon as he dies.
- You do that, frank.
- Yes, sir, Mr. President.
- You call me-- call me, hear?
- Just as soon-- okay.
- Buh-bye now.
- Bye-bye, frank.
- Good-bye-- yeah, okay.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye-bye, frank, buh--
[chuckles]
That was nice, and look what
mother Theresa sent us!
Ohh.
You know, it's true.
One life touches
so many others.
These aren't even his shoes.
What the--
[Buzzer]
- Uh-oh, movie sign!
- Oh, movie sign!
- Oh, doh!
- That way, that way!
Agh!
- [Chuckles]
- You okay, honey?
- Oh, I'm fine.
- Ah!
♪ From the shores
of Albuquerque ♪
[Chuckles]
Oh, this is the Cuba-bemidji
border.
♪♪
[Scoffs]
Yes, that's really Castro.
Look alive, ahem.
Good evening,
Mr. Doobie brother.
That's Castro, you know.
[Distant gunfire]
It's either Castro
or Stuart margolin.
Uhh, my florsheims
are getting muddy.
♪ Hey hey,
we're the monkees ♪
[Laughing]
The massive invasion force
storms the beach.
[Chuckles]
Actually filmed on the moon.
[Splash]
Huh?
- There.
- Ah.
You know, there's steps
right over by the snack bar.
Ow-wee, my army slacks are too
tight and binding, ow.
Was it a good idea
to invade the bay of pigs again
so soon after
the last time?
- No.
- Ohh.
Well, maybe 25 minutes
of training wasn't enough.
Ooh, boy,
I feel tingly.
[Giggling]
Oh, he got the bunny cliff.
I had to follow
the stinky guy.
You kids,
quit invading us there.
Well, we just went up this rope,
but once more can't hurt.
This movie has the courage
to unabashedly repeat itself.
- [Humming]
- [Imitating boinging sound]
♪♪
Uhh!
Ah, there's the nerdy guy
who's gonna get killed.
The mounds view
junior high school production
of "the guns of navarone."
It's the "battle
of the network stars."
Once all seven of them
are into place,
the invasion really begins.
Oh, I'm guessing
that job at Denny's
doesn't seem so bad now,
does it?
Coleman, I think you
sat in ice cream.
Charo could have
planned this invasion better.
Ow!
[Chuckles]
♪ Cockles and mussels,
alive, alive-o ♪
"Get real beard."
It's a leg!
Uhh! Oh.
♪♪
I saw a bobolink!
The a-team.
Ah, Castro lives
above a hardware store.
Fortunately, Cuba has
only eight guys in it.
Damn leftist
guerilla drivers!
Huh?
Oh, there's way more Cuba.
I thought we were done.
Wow, can you imagine
being Castro
and seeing that force
swarming up at ya?
Man.
He's a tactical genius.
That "come here"
gesture?
Brilliant!
By some dreadful
miscalculation,
they've taken over
the old course at St. Andrews.
- Are we there yet?
- I'm hungry.
- My feet hurt.
- I have to go potty!
Just ten more minutes, boys,
then it's time for dinner.
We approach county road "b"
with extreme caution.
This is smart-- they're running
right up Castro's driveway.
Castro's
out raking leaves.
Jeez.
Well, you know, this movie
helped people work through
their feelings
about the bay of pigs.
[Humming]
And thus, the battle
of door county raged on.
[Gunfire]
Ooh.
[Humming]
Ah, pretty sure you're dead.
They just lost
a third of their force.
You know, things look okay.
Actually, maybe Cuba
doesn't need a revolution.
[Humming]
[Gunfire]
He's practically begging
to be fragged.
Mm-hmm.
- Ow, ow!
- Stickers, ow!
- We got prickles!
- Thistles!
Ow-wee.
We fought for control
of the toboggan run.
Hey, no fair, I slipped!
Keep it down,
I'm trying to read in here!
Arto.
"Ah-so"?
[Speaking Spanish]
No, Coleman, don't
take off your pants.
Now, get me
some toilet paper.
The Yankees will pay highly
for you, senor Francis.
[Snoring]
Tragically, he was only looking
for sand dollars.
[Speaking Spanish]
- Hmm.
- Hey, commies are cute.
Mm-hmm.
♪ Night train
to drop the Jeep off ♪
[Laughs]
Obviously, you don't know
who you've captured here.
I'm Coleman Francis.
Hi, I'm here to relieve Deb.
Laura petrie,
revolutionary.
She's the activities director
for the revolution.
Hmm.
This place ain't so bad.
They captured
the frito bandito.
He's Cuban.
- Hmm.
It's a four-star prison.
Recommended
by best leftist.
Oh, that Patty hearst
is at it again.
Tania!
For the sex shot,
let's focus on me
with my legs splayed
and my enormous package
spread out, oh.
[Chuckling]
Their lives
haven't changed at all.
I say, no, it's not pine tar,
it's tobacco juice.
But anyway...
Do we have to sit
so close?
We've got the whole cell.
Hey, Tony, you bring
the book of questions.
Mm, my shin bone is cutting
through my sock here.
I think the phrase
"ugly Americans" is unfair.
- How about you?
- [Laughing]
Say, would you mind
covering up your leg again?
- It's really...
- Hmm?
It's Mel blanc!
Poor guy.
Oh, I can never sleep
during revolutions.
I'm just glad
Coleman's not wearing a skirt.
Thank god.
Stinky-stank redemption.
Honey, put your knees
together, please.
I'm just gonna go
peek in on the girls, I...
Eh, uh--
no, no, I shouldn't.
I really--
I have to control...
Run away,
the ocean's chasing us!
[Whimpers]
[Planes buzzing]
I am a Cuban,
and this is my Cuban infant!
I am a Cuban looking for
Cuban safety here, in Cuba.
Bay of pigs.
That's what they say
when I go swimming.
[Gunfire]
I just can't get worked up
for this war.
You know,
you couldn't lose money
on a bay of pigs film
at this time.
The country
was bay of pigs crazy.
With ya, brother.
Bay of pigs.
Right on.
[Men]
Uhh!
[Indistinct speech]
Huh?
John carradine is really good
in this movie.
Hey, it's justine
or Janine or... j-jorda--
whatever the hell
his name is.
I'm trying to die
over here.
[Gunfire]
[Slurping]
Ugh.
Might as well
get the lawnmower out.
I think he's coming in here
'cause of the editing,
but I can't
tell for sure with...
Oh, no, he's almost in here,
I think.
This may be
so terrifying and...
Nelson eddy?!
It's Joe.
Camina, vago.
Yes, it's Joe.
The loons, Norman,
listen to the loons!
Ah, you don't have to plant
roses that deep.
The longest house in Cuba.
Thought you'd be interested.
The Bridges
of Madison Cuba.
Now, don't run away.
That would be
unfair.
Stay there.
Hey, you're gonna shoot me!
It's Nixon!
Just wait till bebe
hears about this.
His face was tempered by war.
Listo.
Punten.
[All]
Hmm?
♪♪
Disparen!
[Gunshots]
Oh, thanks, now I'm dying,
and I have paint on my face.
Oh, I've heard of this Cuban
paint-throwing.
You never know who's next.
That's what I love
about this crazy place.
I'll go.
- Juan Cruz.
- Hmm?
[Speaking Spanish]
The Cubans in this movie sound
like the grown-ups on "peanuts."
Wah-wah,
wah-wah-wah-wah-wah.
Wah-wah-wah.
♪♪
Jose.
Michelle shocked.
I'll give you eight bucks
for it.
Have you seen this woman?
Goes by Mary,
a.K.A. "The virgin."
El padre, El hijo,
El espiritu Santo.
Amen.
Que dios te salves.
Thanks for playing our game
today.
Vamos!
I've never seen curly so down.
Vamos, Juan Cruz.
Arthur dimmesdale.
Huh.
Quit stalling
and get executed, come on.
Oh, god, that scene's
finally over.
Um, say, I need to order
a low-salt, low-fat last meal,
if that's not a problem.
Okay.
You want the paint
in your face?
That's optional.
Is this a bad time
to ask for a Cuba libre?
Eh, look at this hangnail.
Ever had one
like that?
Ew, my last smoke
is a menthol.
Yuck!
Yeah, well, I suppose, huh?
I wonder who
they're planning on shooting.
Listo.
Mentos.
Punten.
Viva Cuba?
Disparen!
Pull!
[Gunshots]
He seems okay with this.
Missed me, missed me, now you...
Have to... kiss me.
Ugh.
So the rest of the movie
is just watching them all
get shot one by one?
I may enjoy it.
You know, Coleman Francis would
make a really lumpy mattress.
Eww, not that I...
Would someone please
get me a doctor?
I'm George takei.
No doctor
coming here.
You'll have to sweat it out.
Nyah, nyah, nyah.
Managed care at its best.
Oh, for the love
of Pete.
Peek-a-boo!
Who's in there?
Mmm, this looks delicious.
Here,
let Coleman kiss it.
The tender touch
of Coleman Francis.
He won't last 24 hours.
I've seen torn pants
like that before.
Gangrene.
Coleman was pre-med.
Men in prison had it.
The doctor didn't
get to 'em in time.
Somebody get me some water.
I'm dying in a rush.
I don't know much
about executions,
but maybe they could
shoot two at a time, hmm?
The other two guys
went on break.
I'm gonna solo on this one.
No? Okay, fine.
Listo...
They actually made it
a fairly challenging shot.
I've got a very delicate
kidney.
Disparen!
[Gunshots]
Oh, that's great.
[Chuckles]
[Laughter]
Well.
Bye.
Curious George goes to Cuba.
Hey, that's the guy
who just got shot!
Hey, we're next.
He butted.
Must be midnight.
We're gonna let it
all hang down.
[Speaking Spanish]
Wah-wah-wah-wah-wah-wah.
Wah-wah-wah, wah.
They change guards
at midnight.
And they do
light gardening at midnight.
This is getting to be
a drag, guys.
Will somebody
get me some water?
I shot a man
at the Mexican border.
Go to the window.
Ask the guard if a wounded man
can have some water.
I think it'll be funny.
If they give you some,
then we have a chance
to make a break.
They won't give us none.
They know we're all
starving for water.
Tell the guard
he's got a fever.
Go on, try it.
Oh, and, uh,
take your time.
Guard!
- It's me, Margaret.
- Sentry.
Water.
[Snickers]
Man's got a fever.
He got boogie fever.
Just a cupful.
Well, they got a south-facing
cell, that's nice.
I don't have any water.
I've got
a wonderful bouillon here.
I know, I just got killed.
I get that a lot.
I hate these prisons where you
gotta ask for water.
Why don't they just bring it
to the table?
It's not without its charm.
Well, hey, this has little
marshmallows in it.
What'd, it come
out of a magician's kit?
It's bottomless.
Hey, he's double-dipping!
Thanks, guys,
the backwash really helps.
I just gotta look
in the girls' cabin.
Eh-- ooh, no.
Have to control myself.
Control.
Mm, be strong.
That water plan
really went wrong.
Tomorrow night at midnight,
after they change guards,
one guard
will be out front.
The other one
walks around the hut,
when the guard out front
is alone.
No, nothing's sinking in.
Ask him for water.
It's gotta work this time.
Castro looks like
Toulouse-lautrec.
[Laughing]
Why'd they bring
dian fossey?
Ah, fidel had to go
potty behind a tree.
We'd better move out now.
He's here again.
Hmm?
The airstrip we passed
when they captured us.
Can you handle
one of those planes?
I can handle it.
I was in skydivers,
you know.
Cook.
That's the county
Chicago's in.
Ask the guard
for some water.
The movie lapped itself.
If he brings it to you,
I'll be at the window.
Make him
move in close.
How will I know you?
If I can get
my hands on him,
I'll snap his neck.
Don't we wait
for the guard change?
We've got to make it now.
That airstrip--
two, maybe three miles.
You have to give me time
to check.
We need a plane
that's got enough gas.
Take me with you.
It's about that time.
That ranch
I told you about.
It's got a mountain
of pitchblende.
They're practically
giving it away!
Uranium, tungsten--
diamonds, maybe.
Now, look, you've got a busted
leg, and we can't carry you.
I've had it with you!
I'll carry myself.
What kind of a cock-and-bull
story you laying on us?
I'm a bad boy.
There's riches
on my mountain.
Uranium.
The tension mounts.
Tungsten, worth thousands.
Ma-maybe even hundreds.
I-I know
it sounds crazy...
But would you choke me again?
... but I believe him.
What you talkin' 'bout,
Willis?
Griffin,
let's go to Arizona.
I was just beginning to enjoy
new Mexico-slash-Cuba.
Check the window.
And ask the guard for
some water, what the heck.
He's crazy enough
to do it.
He's gonna check the window!
Look at that big old hair grease
stain they're leaving there.
Ugh.
Is the film grainy, or are
these guys just kind of grainy?
Water... thirsty.
Sick man.
Uh, things you'd say
to a guard!
Uh, things in a prison!
Pass, pass...
I don't think
he's going to buy it.
Ask him again.
Come on, improvise a little.
Water!
Thirsty.
Sick man.
Uh, things you get
from a tap.
Things you
call your grandpa.
Things you--
oh, move on, please!
Water.
Oh, please,
I'm not a huggy person-- agh!
He's dead already,
so it's a lot easier.
♪♪
Oh, the jumping training
pays off.
I stand corrected.
[Giggles]
Huh? What the--
[laughter]
Escape from "green acres."
[Shouting in Spanish]
♪♪
Achtung!
I mean, allons-y!
Uh, zut alors!
Wait, i'm...
Oh, it's daytime now.
Hee hee, well, they ran
into ye olde mining town.
[Gunshot]
Water... thirsty.
Sick man.
It's nighttime again.
And day.
♪ Night and day,
da da da da ♪
[Whimpers]
The airstrip˯ oughta be
over that way.
Let's go.
The bronko nagurski gang!
[Laughing]
[Humming]
[Whistling]
Join me and Che Guevara
as we go hunting mercenaries.
♪ Hello muddah, faddah ♪
Yep, I'm Cuban.
Huh?
I mean, 'Kay.
[Speaking French]
Uh, uh... oh.
Today's guard
wears stylish flairs.
Actionlessness!
Ah, whew!
I wasn't that close, huh?
Well, that one's okay.
I'm not wild
about the interior.
I turned everything on--
the radio, the lights.
Ah.
Darn good thing they escaped
during the Cuban aircraft expo.
Look at him run,
the little femme.
Look, peanuts aren't important--
just take one!
A fortune in pitch blend
is riding on this scene.
I'm gonna put my wig on,
see if that helps any.
That's good.
Huh?
♪♪
[Chuckling]
Good, Rick.
Uh, "d" for drive...
"F" must mean fly, hmm.
Let's go.
♪♪
He's using
Coleman's slipstream.
Well...
Oh, please, I'm in enough
trouble already!
Fuzzy thurston
is the fugitive!
[Laughing]
Hey, moe, moe!
Let go of the camera!
Please go!
Wub-wub-wub-wub-wub-wub-wub!
Ngh, ngh, ngh, ngh!
- Oh...
- Helping?
- No, not at all.
- Hmm.
They look cute.
Those whitewalls really kind of
screw up the camouflage, huh?
♪♪
[Engine puttering]
[Coughing]
You know, I still like this
movie better than "Havana."
Oh, yeah.
[Gunshots]
Oh...
[Grunting]
Come on, you guys, my boss
is gonna be really mad!
What?
[Gunshots]
All right, tay!
Pull... pull...
Pull!
♪♪
[Gunfire]
Just ignore them,
rise above it.
Whoo, whew!
Boy, that was close.
They made it, though.
Next, we visit
lovely busch gardens.
Well, in some parts of Cuba,
it was a nice day.
Stay off the road
and keep your eyes open.
If you see anything, film--
I will put it in.
Coleman, are we still
in a plane in Cuba?
It's all an elaborate plan
to find a nice picnic spot.
They should have tried to take
over Belize or grand Cayman.
Would have been easier
for their first time.
Huh, so that's tungsten.
Thought it
would be cooler.
Whoa, little dog poopy there.
Under the spreading
Coleman Francis,
the village smithy stands.
It says,
"viva frogs' legs."
Ohh, man, don't tempt me.
Mmm.
Is that the lunch wall
or the dinner wall?
I am the dark specter
of food.
I sensed there was mail.
I have a frog leg place
over there.
Great,
my "wall street journal."
[Sniffing]
Uhh!
Whoa!
Gave myself a snuggie there.
Frog legs...
Let's get us some!
I gotta get me
a mechanical bull.
[Sighs]
Location, location,
location.
Just look at that
curb appeal, huh?
♪♪ [Piano playing]
You think
I'm dressed for it?
[Chuckles]
My name is death.
I'll be your waiter.
What can I do for you, boys?
Do you have
any catfish?
Coffee.
Coffee coming up.
Ah, coffee,
a Coleman Francis motif.
The kitchen guy
just died, sorry.
My father was a can opener,
and my mother was a wood duck.
A pie doesn't make you
want to kill yourself.
You want some?
Who's playing that piano?
That's my daughter.
She's wed
to the devil.
She's been blind,
you know,
since her husband
got killed in the war.
That makes sense.
We got an omelet called
"supercalifragilistic-
expial-delicious."
Doctors have done
everything for her.
- Tried glasses?
- Nothing.
Spent all of my money.
Sure, we're gonna
put her down.
Since that freeway went in,
lost all our business.
I guess
it's not much use trying.
[Sighs]
May as well fold up
and pull out.
But I have my health,
and my spirits are high.
We have a wonderful
oktoberfest frog leg.
♪♪
Sitting in on chifforobe.
[Laughing]
You see,
they're just jealous.
He was showing off,
well, with his daughter
and his ritzy restaurant
and all.
♪♪
Whoo! Surprisingly quick out of
the blocks, this fellow.
[Chuckles]
Okay, slow down.
Speed up.
Slow down.
♪♪
You and your swank restaurant
and your chichi frog legs!
Suppose you boys'll
be wanting your check.
Oh!
I'm gonna have to ask you
to leave if this continues.
Ow!
"Apple's way" is different
than I remember.
[Giggles]
Now, where in Cuba do you
suppose they are?
Not the frog mine, no!
Eh, heh,
I kind of like it.
Saddle me up, boys!
Aaaaaah...
Ohh...
Splash!
There, now we have the rest
of the day to ourselves.
♪♪ [Woman singing soprano]
The legendary
singing buick!
How are they gonna get the car
down a well?
Check that junk box,
see if it'll run.
All right.
I just keep thinking
of those tasty frog legs.
Ah, home of the famous
steak ala weismeyer.
The lure of the siren.
♪♪ [Piano playing]
♪♪ [Singing continues]
I heartily endorse
throwing her down a well.
Hey look, tab hunter
lives here.
What do you know.
You know, the freeway
may not be the problem.
Yeah.
♪♪
Forget that,
where did he get the wig?
Oh, hi, Ms. Channing!
What's new?
Oh, I'm not Carol Channing.
Oh, thank goodness,
Mike.
You must be feeling
a little bit--
I'm t-bone Burnett.
Uh-huh.
That's not right either.
Hold on.
I'm Vicki Lawrence.
Eh, uh...
[Sighs]
Then again...
Maybe I should just go
lie down for a while.
- That's a great idea, honey.
- Yeah, bye-bye.
You lie down.
It's the movie,
don't worry, okay?
It'll be just fine.
We better check
on his nibs.
Oh, yeah, right.
♪ It's a marshmallow world
in the winter ♪
No, those are my pants!
Quigley down under, help me!
Help!
There, there, Dr. F.
There, there.
Well, Mike,
it's not looking good.
I'm afraid we may
be at the end.
- Frank?
- Yes?
Frank.
Yes, Dr. F.?
- Frank!
- I'm right here, Dr. F.
- Frank?
- What?
- Frank!
- Yes, Dr. F.
- What?!
Frank, I'm going down
a long hallway.
There's a figure
at the end beckoning to me.
Well, don't you think you ought
to go to him then, doctor?
Frank... there's something
I've always wanted to tell you.
Look, let's not make
a big production out of this.
There's a guy
down at the end of the hallway
waiting for you, okay?
Yes, he's tapping his foot
and looking at his watch.
Well, don't you think
you ought to go to him, then?
[Grunting]
Oh, frank...
- Yes?
- This is it.
I--
hyah.
And... it is done.
Dr. Clayton.
No, wait.
I'm alive.
No.
I'm dead.
Yes.
No.
Now I'm dead.
Wait.
I'm still alive.
No.
I'm dead.
Wait.
I can't die.
I've got too much
to live for.
[Fabric ripping]
I've got my good friend frank.
I've got... things!
Uh, things
that I gotta... do!
I gotta live and laugh
and love
and live
and embrace the world!
I wanna live!
Ohh! Joe!
Hi!
[Grunting, impact blows]
That hurt!
Ohh! Ooh hoo!
How you doing, better?
It still hurts.
♪♪
Should have had
those frog legs.
Pull over.
Get that top up.
Coleman, you brat!
Chinese fire drill.
So, the frog legs
were real good, huh, guys?
This is cinema verite
to the ultimate.
You know, your everyday
annoyances should not be filmed.
[Wind whistling]
Hey guys, I'm gonna
change the tape, 'Kay?
'Kay?
When we get this top up,
we're gonna drive back to Cuba
and do it right this time.
Aha.
Spend it at cliff weismeyer's!
Thanks, that helps.
I was getting cold.
[Humming]
♪♪
Ooh, there's that new overpass
I was telling you about.
So the Cuban stuff,
just a digression.
Now the movie
can really begin.
- Yeah.
- Would you stop?
♪♪
Remember when everyone started
dressing like these guys?
Excuse me, is this the...
♪ Night train
to mundo fine ♪
[Laughter]
Hmm, carradine tracks--
two, three days old.
They've stumbled
into the end of "mod squad"!
♪♪
[Humming]
♪ Night train to mundo fine ♪
♪ hey, hey, hey, yeah ♪
We're gonna let
the air out of the tires.
[Laughing]
Hey, Griffin,
the train's moving out.
Come on, landis,
grab the front end.
Come on, cook, let's go.
What the--
what was wrong with the car?
They had a perfectly
good car.
All right, go on up.
All this to get
to the hobo gathering.
Come on top, cook,
come on.
I bet they're gonna pistol-whip
Thomas the tank engine.
This train is bound
for glory, this train...
[Train whistle blows]
Shaft did it better.
I think the club car's
up this way.
Boy, this movie
doesn't let up.
Wow.
[Whistles]
The train-riding sequence
was omitted for clarity.
I see this as a bed
and breakfast.
Can you see it?
We need transportation.
Yeah.
We're gonna go legit.
I'm gonna open
a Claire's boutique.
I don't want
any more bulls chasing me.
Landis,
give me the ring.
That's my Archie
fan club ring.
I can't
give you this ring.
My dad gave it to me.
I don't care if Moses
gave it to you.
Give me the ring.
You're not gonna get it.
[Giggling]
Oh! Hope that's a gun
he pulled out.
Uhh!
Ah, my neck got broken
in that jump cut.
Well, see, the movie has finally
thrown up its hands
and said,
"I just don't know."
I want to hurt this movie,
but I can never hurt it
the way it hurt me.
Did they even
need to go to Cuba?
I was lucky to pick up
one of these rebuilt girls.
Candy, take the groceries
in the house.
What house?
- The blue Chevy.
- Oh.
Ah, my prize alternator.
Yellow ribbon
at the state fair.
I think the location scout
was a spaz.
Hey, it's Dominick
and Eugene and curly.
[Laughing]
I'm gonna build
my own artificial hip.
[Humming]
Can I help
you fellas?
Got something cheap?
I have a nail
I can sell you.
You mean it?
Oh, Coleman,
I'm touched.
It's worth a few bucks.
What's the hole
in it for?
What do you got
that we can have?
It's pretty.
[Humming]
Guh!
I'm gonna look at it
all day.
It's shiny and stuff.
♪♪
[Engine starting]
Now please, god,
say "the end," please.
And now,
a trip to uncle Bob's farm.
Okay, okay, what plots
need resolving?
Well, there's
the guy in the well.
They gotta do something
about Cuba.
Hmm.
Oh, another cheery
Coleman Francis character.
Well, master says
you can't stay here.
I understand they did 70 takes
of the window scene.
We now return to
"in cold blood," the series.
No, uh-uh, don't bring
your movie here.
No, get out, go!
[Scoffs] Now it becomes
a lighthearted domestic comedy.
[Laughing]
Uh, wanna buy a candy
to send kids like us to Cuba?
Ruby chastain?
Yes.
We're friends
of your husband.
My husband is Amanda bearse.
You know Bailey?
Sure, I put my face
in his wound.
We was with him in Cuba.
Please... come in.
And we're in.
♪♪
Oh, my dinner party
isn't going very well.
I knew you wouldn't mind
if I wore my Teddy.
I didn't want him to go.
But Bailey...
Wanted to go.
Well, he had ideas.
Bad ideas.
He was headstrong,
to say the least.
Yum, yeah, headstrong.
[Munching sounds]
Well, his grandparents
meant a lot to him.
His green pants
meant a lot to him?
He thought he owed them for
helping him through college.
That's why we have a picture
of gene pitney on the mantle.
As I said, my husband's...
More coffee?
As I said, he was alive,
but I'm afraid
our friend Bailey is dead.
Yeah, it's
a real tragedy.
Anyway, pass the salt there,
will you?
To think that
I was once Betty boop.
Bailey told me
to move out.
Live in town
till he returned.
And then come back here
till he leaves again.
But this is my home.
I live
under the sink.
It's been lonely here.
His face a mask
of sensitivity.
But I couldn't leave.
Mm-hmm.
I wanted a nice home
in town once.
Well, no use letting that stuff
up in the hills go to waste.
Good point,
whoever said that.
I don't know how much
we owe on our place.
Three or four dollars.
We do owe some,
I know that.
I'd be willing
to divide with you,
if there's something
worth dividing.
Have any idea
where the mine is located?
Up in the mountains.
I was
up there once.
Yeah, that's nice.
How long did you
simmer the sauce?
Maybe he won't come back.
Will you move back
into town then, or...
Never knew I would
miss him so.
Much.
You never know how much you miss
somebody till they leave you.
I wanted
to bring Bailey home.
He couldn't make it.
Turns out, he's a natural
at grief counseling.
If there's something
up on that mountain
worth having,
we'll find it.
Ah, great.
You have any more
tuna helper, ma'am?
We'll have to take plenty
of water, food.
Got a couple
of shovels in the back.
Anything else
we may need?
Uh, underpants.
There's a geiger counter
here someplace.
We'll check
on that tomorrow.
May as well get some rest.
You men
must be worn out.
I'll get some quilts
for you.
It looks a lot like Cuba
out here, but just ignore that.
I get the lawn chair
next time.
Ah, I think my life
is finally coming together.
Morning and Coleman
just go together.
The one who looks like curly
is so cute.
Hey, mind if we
sunbathe nude?
[Rooster crowing]
It's morning in purgatory!
Mrs. Chastain,
you sure cook fine vittles.
Mmm, makes you laugh
and sing.
♪♪
♪ everybody's having fun
and smoking ♪
♪ and the dogs
are eating food ♪
I feel good.
♪♪
♪ robbing people, killing
people, hopping trains is fun ♪
Bet you he smells like
Jack del rio's jockstrap.
♪♪
This is the last of the cat.
Enjoy.
[Humming]
♪♪
♪ it's lovely weather
for a sleigh ride ♪
♪ together with you ♪
The huge,
huge face!
[Humming]
I gotta pick up
some wax worms.
♪ Just hear those
sleigh bells ringaling ♪
♪ ting-ting-tingaling too ♪
I tell you, if my mood
picks up any more,
I might not even
kill myself.
Are the pigs' knuckles
on the shelf all you have?
You want a video?
We got some super violent
Asian triple-x cartoons.
That'll be $5.05.
♪ Outside the snow is falling
and, oh, calling yoo-hoo ♪
There's a coupon for free
canning on your receipt.
Well, thanks
for not killing me.
Right neighborly of you.
Okay, Coleman,
we got cheetos,
but we're not opening them
until later, understood?
Ohh.
You get my lactaid pills?
So you can see
that with the proper planning,
you can make your car trip
happy and successful.
♪♪
Hymie!
I like being
at a stakeout with you, Max.
Uhh, even when it's bright,
it's dark in this movie.
♪♪
- Steve.
- Yeah?
Who are we?
Take a look.
The gay high school
secret service.
I better contact Kelly.
Do whatever you want,
I gotta go to class.
Kelly, this is Steve.
We've spotted the fugitives.
See?
Right, Kelly.
Stan, let's go.
I talked to Kelly!
Can't you just
smell the tungsten?
And they managed to find another
beautiful location!
Have you guys ever read
"the total filmmaker"
by Coleman Francis?
Anybody want to do some peyote
and fly over canyons?
Is that the mountain?
Let's kill
that mountain.
That's the mountain.
Kelly, this is tensley.
Sheriff, there's
a copter waiting at the airport.
Okay, meet me at the airport
in ten minutes.
Kelly commands such
loyalty from his men.
It's okay.
Well, that was a cul-de-sac,
wasn't it?
[Laughter]
It's "westworld" now.
♪♪
Jim bakker!
I'm jolly Bob.
[Laughter]
Hope you guys don't mind.
I dressed like
an old time sheriff.
They had to call in
the volunteer filmmaker squad
to end the movie.
Helicopter
is over here waiting.
Fine.
Ready, tensley?
- I think so.
- Okay, let's go.
♪♪
So when does somebody
run all the way to hell?
Whoa, ho, ho, ho, now step back
and think, guys.
Are we all gonna fit in here?
Psh, these idiots, god.
Oh, I'm Kelly,
I get a helicopter.
I'm Kelly, I rule everybody.
Can I ride
with you tensely?
Yeah, okay, sure.
[Sighs]
I think this is taking place
in mordor.
Oh, how I long for Cuba.
I just wanted to get out
and look at the car again.
I can't get enough of them
opening the hood.
Killed in Vietnam.
Here, lick this.
We're out of oil.
Here, let me squeeze some
out of my pants pocket.
[Grunting]
We'd better go back.
- Hmm?
- Oh, but we just got here.
Tor no go back.
Nobody's going back.
♪♪
Coleman, now, count to ten.
So they're not
in Cuba anymore, right?
Nothing's happening
so fast.
Maybe now would be
a good time to put my hands
on my knees and rotate.
Ah, heh heh.
[Gunshot]
Oh.
Oh, I wish I were
less impulsive.
I'm still
going legit, though!
[Humming]
Scotty, beam us up.
A wild curly can hit 30 miles
an hour when threatened.
Well, looks like we caught us
two of the tungsten trio.
Epilogue.
Somewhere behind that tree,
there's a scene happening.
♪♪
Huh?
[Scoffs]
Please do not reveal
the incredible secret
of "red zone Cuba."
[Humming]
Oh, sorry.
Uh, no camping here, ma'am.
[Sobbing]
I killed a cute little wabbit.
Why is Phil silvers
rounding up corpses?
Hmm, just don't slam
the tailgate too hard.
♪♪
The gene krupa band
pulls into town.
[Tires screech]
The wherever-this-is TV!
Ah, Janet Reno's
moving in to end the film.
Woodstock 3
draws a slim crowd.
A male curly can run for hours
on little water.
This is a really
stupid use of a split screen.
Native beaters are used
to flush out the curly.
Oh, look up there,
it's smelly Kelly in his heli.
Ah, we're just as good as you,
Kelly!
Well, I see she bought
more lawn ornaments.
Got a load of wife for you.
They shouldn't have skimped
on their privacy fence.
They hate ankles.
Great job on the bay of pigs,
honey.
She's a little
awkward to carry.
You got a two-Wheeler
in the garage?
Khh! Oww!
[Growling]
And when a curly dies
in the wild,
he provides food
for other curlys.
That was him, wasn't it?
What the hell.
The cast of "how to succeed
in business" moves in.
The young, fresh fellows.
Hard to love
a character for so long
and to see him come
to such an end.
Mother of mercy,
is this the end of curly?
Hey, he's got donuts
in his pockets.
Huh?
[Thunder rumbling]
Griffin.
Ran all the way to hell
with a penny
and a broken cigarette.
Which is really all you need
in hell, so it works out great.
Huzzah, it's gone!
I thought they portrayed 1961
quite well.
Hmm, not too hard,
since they made it in '65.
Doh! Psha!
♪ Night train ♪
[All groaning]
You know,
aside from the fact
that I'll never again
experience joy in my life,
I don't think
"red zone Cuba"
had any kind of negative effect
on me.
Yeah, even
being Carol Channing
didn't shield me from
the effects of this one.
[All sigh]
Well, hey, I know what we can do
to cheer ourselves up.
Let's sing us
a bouncy, upbeat song, okay?
- Okay.
- Okay, great idea!
Hit it, cambot!
♪♪
[all laughing]
Whoo! Yay!
♪ Oh, whenever I want to cry
and bawl ♪
- ♪ because I'm feeling sad ♪
- yeah?
♪ I think of
ironing boards and drywall ♪
♪ and then I don't
feel so bad ♪
♪ whenever
I'm feeling down and blue ♪
- ♪ and sorry for myself ♪
- uhh!
♪ I get some staples
and some glue ♪
- ♪ and I'm happy as an elf ♪
- [laughs]
♪ Whenever I start
to mope and pout ♪
♪ and there's nothing left
in my soul ♪
♪ I check the toilet paper
and if we're out ♪
♪ I buy another roll ♪
♪ have you ever
touched a post-it note ♪
♪ have you ever looked
at boots ♪
♪ have you ever
sat down in a chair ♪
♪ have you ever used
a paper clip ♪
♪ so if you listen
to our advice ♪
♪ and you wanna feel terrific ♪
♪ do things that make you
feel nice ♪
♪ I wish we could
be more specific ♪
[Groaning]
Ow! Oh! Oh! Agh!
Ohh! Ooh...
♪♪
♪♪ [Piano playing]